"他见黑影渐渐靠近
"As he saw the dark figure approaching,
挺直了上身想看得清楚些
"he rose up for a better view,
完全没有意识到他迈向了死亡"
"little knowing he was heading for his doom."
我知道你俩的感受  听这句
I know, right? Oh, and listen to this.
"致我的导师  理查德·卡塞尔
"To my mentor, Richard Castle,
没有他的支持与指导
"without whose support and guidance
本书永不会有出版之日"
"this book never would've seen the light of day."
你不过就是给艾利克斯·康拉德的
All you did was give Alex Conrad
手稿提了点建议  发给了你的出版商
a few notes on his manuscript then send it to your publisher.
他才是此书的作者
He was the one who wrote the book.
你那么理解也行  在我看来
Mm. That's your version. In my version...
我温柔地呵护了这天才的星星之火
I gently fostered the glowing embers of talent,
将其烧成文学上的燎原之焰
fanning them into a literary wildfire.
他会来城里
He's gonna be in town
邀我跟他聚聚
and asked to get together with me.
想多向我学学写作过程
He wants to learn more about my writing process.
"过程"  你该不会是指
And by "process," you mean your procrastination
你不到最后一秒决不写作的拖沓毛病
until the very last second.
在过量咖啡因的作用下
And then writing out of a desperate panic
-几近抓狂的完成作品吗  -是这个
- in a caffeine-induced haze? - That one?
不  不是
No, not that one.
是指我通过跟随纽约警察
The one where I find authenticity
调查研究详实的第一手资料这一点
by doing hands-on research with the NYPD.
我跟艾利克斯今天约在分局见面
So I'm having Alex meet me at the precinct later on today.
贝克特会激动死的
Beckett will be thrilled with that.
贝克特  我想她不会介意的
Beckett? I'm sure she won't mind.
你还没告诉她
You haven't told her yet?
我确信她不会介意的
I am sure she will be fine with it.
不介意  我怎么就不会介意了
Fine with it? Why would I be fine with it?
好吧  我很抱歉
Okay. I'm sorry.
他就是个作家
Come on. He's a writer.
能惹多大麻烦啊
How much trouble could he possibly be?
你这是同意了吗
So is that a yes?
不同意
Is--is that a no?
-蕾妮  -你好
- Hey, Lanie. - Hey.
-死者是谁  -扎克·林赛
- Who's this? - Zack Lindsey,
是纽约大学泳队的优秀队员
a stand-out on the U.N.Y. swim team.
或者说他溺死前曾是
Or he was before he drowned.
游泳健将怎么会溺死
How does a champion swimmer drown?
-有人"帮"了他一把  -灼伤
- He had help. - Burns?
是某种腐蚀性物质
From a caustic substance.
有人把浸过那种物质的布捂到他脸上
Someone put a rag to his face soaked in the stuff.
他被气味熏昏了过去
He passed out from the fumes,
然后被扔进泳池里溺死了  根据水温
then was dumped in the pool to drown. Based on water
和体温判断  他死于今晨1点到5点之间
and body temp, I'd say between 1:00 and 5:00 this morning.
究竟是什么物质
And what was the substance?
得把他弄回实验室去才能知道
I won't know till I get him back to the shop.
-谁发现的  -扎克的队友  他们早上
- Who found him? - Zack's teammates when they showed up
六点来游泳训练
for 6 a.m. swim practice.
那去跟他队友谈谈
All right. Let's talk to his teammates.
看看有没有人跟扎克不合  查查
Find out if anyone had it in for Zack, and let's figure out
他们1点到5点之间都在哪里
where they were between 1:00 and 5:00 a.m.
我去跟扎克教练谈谈
I'll go talk to Zack's coach.
看到他躺在那里
It just doesn't seem real,
感觉这一切是那么的虚幻
seeing him lying there like that.
他那么晚了在做什么
What was he doing here so late?
训练
Training.
这孩子离不了泳池
Couldn't keep that kid outta the pool.
两周前
Two weeks ago,
他在比赛前食物中毒
he got food poisoning right before a meet.
病得一塌糊涂  差点没把胆汁吐出来
Sick as a dog, just puking his guts out.
我让他退赛  但他硬撑了过来
I told him to withdraw, but he toughed it out,
赢了参加的所有项目
won all his events.
这就是扎克
But that was zack.
他将成为下一个罗博·特维克
He was gonna be the next Rob Tredwyck
或是迈克尔·菲尔普斯
or Michael Phelps.
他个人生活有麻烦吗
Did he have any personal problems?
他是来自本森赫斯特的孩子
He was a kid from Bensonhurst, you know?
我给他争取了部分奖学金
I got him a partial scholarship,
他一直都是自己坚强的生活
but he lived on his own all the way out there
-因为他只付得起那么多  -他父母呢
- because it's all he could afford. - What about his parents?
他父亲去世了
Uh, his dad's gone.
他妈妈搬去了大西洋城工作
His, uh, mom had to move to Atlantic ity for work.
我
I...
承诺过会照顾好他
promised I was gonna look out for him.
游泳队呢
What about the swim team?
这里肯定有他的竞争对手
There must have been some rivalries there.
他和布莱恩·莫里斯最有希望赢得
He and Brian Morris were our two best chances
本周的锦标赛  但是没发生过冲突
to win the tournament this week, but there was no bad blood,
不管是跟布莱恩还是跟别人
not with Brian or anyone else on the team.
好吧  但我还是需要队员名单
Okay, I'm still gonna need a team roster
以及所有能进出泳池的人员名单
and a list of all the people who had access to this pool.
我先失陪了
Uh... Excuse me.
就因为这个  阿丽克西斯别想上大学了
This is why Alexis is never going to college.
-想听点奇怪的事吗  -说
- You want to hear something crazy? - Yeah.
我跟夜间看门人谈过了
I was talking to the night janitor.
他昨晚待到一点半
He was here till 1:30 last night,
但他看到扎克和另一个人在一起
but he saw Zack with another guy.
知道那人是谁吗
Do we have a name?
连照片都有  "火箭"罗博·特维克
We have a picture, too. "Rocket" Rob Tredwyck.
伙计来笑一个
Give us a big smile, mate.
没错就这样
Yes, like that.
你爱这个男人  你想要他
You love this man. You want him.
真搞笑  我也想"要"他
That's funny. I want him, too.
这家伙在水中所向披靡
The guy was invincible in water.
简直不能相信他居然溺死了
I can't believe he'd drown.
-你怎么认识他的  -三年前一次锦标赛
- How did you know him? - From a tournament, three years ago.
我去参加北京奥运会的时候扎克还是个新手
Zack was a freshman while I was headed to Beijing.
我能看出他很特别
I could tell he was special.
就像看到了年轻版的我
It was like looking at a younger version of me.
他真有那么棒
He was really that good?
是啊  不过我不是那个意思
Yeah, but, uh, that's not what I meant.
大多数练游泳的孩子都是冲着钱来的
Most kids in this sport, they come from money.
扎克和我都在苦日子里长大
Zack and me, we both grew up hard.
所以我罩着他
So I took him under my wing.
听起来你像是他的导师
Sounds like you were kind of a mentor to him.
不过是照顾自己人
I was just looking out for my own.
那昨晚你在泳池做什么
So what were you doing at the pool last night?
扎克说想练两把  我就想
Zack said he wanted to run drills, and I figured,
没搞错吧
what the hell?
我退役了  不常在水里训练
Now that I'm retired, I don't do enough time in the water.
但是我感觉他就是需要一个朋友
But I think he really just needed a friend.
为什么这么说
Why is that?
他刚和他女朋友谈过
He just had the talk with his girl.
谈孩子是怎么生出来的吗
Where do babies come from?
不是谈那个
No, not that talk.
而是像我还在维明顿的时候
The one I had with my high school girlfriend
跟我女朋友谈的那种
back in Wilmington.
如果想成为顶尖高手
If you want to get to the top,
你就不能让任何人拖累你
you can't take everyone with you.
有些人你必须放手
So some people, you have to leave behind.
-所以就得谈谈  -她如何应对的
- So you have the talk. - And how did she handle that?
她挺伤心的  扎克也是
She took it hard. So did Zack.
但他很担心她
But he was worried about her,
担心她会做出什么傻事
worried that she might do something stupid.
你还记得她名字吗
Do you remember her name?
布丽吉特  布丽吉特·麦克马尼斯
Bridget. Bridget McManus.
你昨晚什么时候离开泳池的
And what time did you leave the pool last night?
刚过午夜
A little after midnight.
你早上一点到五点在哪里
Where were you between 1:00 and 5:00 a.m.?
和广告代理商的一些人在菩萨酒吧
At Buddha Bar with half the ad agency.
我们一直玩到天亮
We partied till dawn.
到你了  火箭
We're ready for you, Rocket.
天
Man...
推销古龙水还真是很费力啊
Hell of a day to sell cologne.
你在看什么
What were you looking at?
没什么
Nothing.
我第一次带他去泳池的时候  他才两岁
First day I put him in the pool, he was 2 years old.
他就像条鱼一样
Took to it like a fish.
你有孩子吗
You have kids?
两个女儿  一个儿子
Two daughters and a son.
这是我们该做的  对吧
It's what we do for them, right?
他爸走了之后
When his dad left
当我感觉万念俱灰的时候
and I was feeling lower than dirt,
你知道他和我说了什么吗
you know what he told me?
他说"为了你  我总有一天会成名"  妈
He said, "I'm gonna be someone one day for you, Ma,
这样你在大街上走也能为我骄傲
so you can walk down the street and be proud."
是谁干的
Who did this?
是谁杀了我的儿子
Who killed my son?
我们会竭尽全力查出真相的
We're doing everything we can to find out.
蒂诺威夫人  你知道关于
Ms. Dinovi, what can you tell me
布丽吉特·麦克马尼斯的事吗
about Bridget McManus?
她和扎克从高中开始就在一起了
Her and Zack have been an item since high school.
这和布丽吉特有什么关系吗
What's this got to do with Bridget?
可能没什么  我们只是要确认每个细节
Maybe nothing, we're just checking everywhere.
他有提起过别的吗  有没有什么麻烦
Did he mention anything else, any trouble he might be in?
扎克知道什么是麻烦  他从来不参与其中
Zack knew what trouble was. He wanted no part of it.
我们这儿的人很难走出去
People don't get out of our neighborhood.
扎克就要成功了
Zack was gonna make it.
我的宝贝  他马上就要成功了
My baby, he was going to make it.
队长
Captain.
那是扎克的母亲
Zack's mom.
有关于女朋友的线索吗
Anything about the girlfriend?
她不知道
Not that she knows of.
在她看来一切都好
She seemed to think everything was okay.
有很多事他都没和他妈说
Ah, then there was a lot he wasn't sharing.
看看布丽吉特在扎克遇害的那个晚上
Check out the text messages that Bridget fired off to Zack
给他发的短信
on the night he was killed.
看上去可不太愉快
Ooh. Not a lot of "LOLs" in there.
"扎克  如果你离开我
"Zack, if you leave me,
我对天发誓  我会杀了你"
I swear to god, I'll kill you."
看来她挺毒舌的
She has a way with words.
而且还有犯罪记录
And a record to go with it.
行为不检  大多不严重
Disorderly conduct. Mostly minor stuff.
警员正在把她带过来
Uniforms are bringing her in now.
这里说她只有5英尺2英寸[约1米6]
It says here she's 5'2".
你觉得她真的能够制服扎克吗
You really think she could overpower zack?
不  但是她兄弟可以
Uh, no, but her brothers could.
和大多数爱尔兰人一样  她有四个兄弟
In grand Irish tradition, she has four of them,
每个人都超过6英尺  每个都臭名昭著
each over 6 foot, each with his own claim to fame--
蓄意袭击
Assaults...
-严重蓄意袭击  -糟糕
- Ag. Assault... - Bad.
ADW  殴打
A.D.W. , battery...
袭击停车部门执法人员
assault on city employee, parking enforcement.
那个不算
Doesn't count.
-小心点  -伙计
- Easy. - Dude.
开玩笑而已
I--just jokes.
查出她几个兄弟在早上1点和5点之间
All right, find out where her brothers were
都在哪里
between 1:00 and 5:00 a.m.
卡塞尔和我去和布丽吉特谈谈
Castle and I will talk to Bridget.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
杀了他
Kill him?
我从九年级开始就爱着扎克·林赛
I've loved Zack Lindsey since the ninth grade.
那你的示爱方式很有趣
You have a funny way of showing it.
我只是很生气
I was pissed.
五年了  是我帮他做的清蒸鸡胸肉
For five years, I cooked his steamed chicken breast,
每天凌晨1点前  是我把他的通心粉
I put his pasta in the tupperware
放进饭盒里  是我在健身房陪着他
before 1:00 in the morning, I kept him company at the gym.
然后他告诉我"对不起  布丽吉特
And then he tells me, "Sorry, Bridge.
我不能受到其他干扰"
I can't have any other voices in my head."
好像突然之间  我让他心烦意乱了
Like suddenly, I'm a distraction.
突然之间  我配不上科泉市了吗
Like suddenly, I'm not good enough for Colorado Springs?
所以你就威胁要杀了他  除非跟你和好
So you threatened to kill him unless he took you back?
我就是这么说话的  行不
No, that's how I talk, okay?
但的确有事情不对劲
But there was something going on.
和游泳一点关系都没有
And it had nothing to do with swimming.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
最近他焦虑不安  还神神秘秘的
Lately, he had been stressed, secretive.
还有他还说"我的时代来了"
Add that to him saying, "This is my time,"
还有那些多金的大学女孩看他的样子
and the way those rich college girls looked at him.
我不是小孩  我猜得出来
I wasn't born yesterday. I can do the math.
你觉得他有外遇了
You thought there was someone else.
没错
Oh, yeah.
于是有天晚上他出了公寓  我就跟踪了他
So I followed him out of his apartment the other night,
准备去揍扁某个康涅狄格州的大贱人
ready to fight some queen bitch from Connecticut.
抢回我男人  不过他见的不是女孩
For what's mine, only it wasn't another girl.
那是谁
Well, who was it?
我不知道  一个长得挺吓人的家伙
I don't know. Some scary looking guy.
他们在地铁站碰了头
They met under the L,
就开始大喊大叫
and they went at it, yelling and screaming.
那个家伙有口音
I couldn't tell about what, though,
所以我听不出他们在讲什么
'cause the guy had, like, an accent.
什么样的口音  西班牙  亚洲  俄罗斯
What kind of accent-- Spanish, Asian, Russian?
我看上去像是在联合国的人吗
Do I look like I work at the U.N.?
反正不是布鲁克林的口音
Not Brooklyn, okay?
好的  不
Okay. No...
总之  我事后问过扎克
Anyways, I asked Zack about it afterwards,
他说没什么  但肯定有什么事
and he said it was nothing, but it wasn't.
你能向我们的画像师描述一下这个人吗
Do you think you could describe this guy to our sketch artist?
蕾妮确定了他体内没有药物
So Lanie confirms no drug in his system,
或者兴奋剂什么的
performance-enhancing or otherwise.
从他血液内高浓度的氯离子来看
And from the high levels of chloride ion in his blood,
她能肯定那些灼伤是因为氯
she is sure that the burns came from chlorine.
我们有着重口音的凶手
Hmm. So our heavily accented killer
用沾满氯水的布将扎克弄晕了
rendered Zack unconscious with a chlorine-soaked rag.
我们不确定他就是凶手
We don't know that he's a killer.
这是一个无辜的人的脸吗
Is this the face of an innocent man?
他在被害人被杀前一晚
He had a heated argument with our victim
和他有过激烈的争执
the night before he was killed.
那他的动机又会是什么呢
And what would his motive be exactly?
他...如果...
He... If...
我或许有点线索
I... may have a line on that.
我查了一下扎克的财务状况
I'm looking at Zack's financials.
这个家伙只得到了部分奖学金
The guy only had a partial scholarship.
他仍付得起大多数学费
He still paid for most of his tuition,
书本费还有生活费
books, and living expenses,
都没有依靠学生贷款
all without taking student loans.
他没有工作  而他妈也只能勉强度日
He didn't have a job, and his mom was just squeaking by.
全国大学体育协会的规定
And NCAA rules
禁止他接受除了他家庭之外
preclude him from receiving any financial assistance
的任何经济支助
from outside his family.
那他从哪里搞到的钱
So where did he get that money?
也许他从错误的人那里
You think maybe he borrowed money from the wrong guys
借钱来资助他的梦想
to finance his dream?
然后他还不了钱
And when he couldn't make the payments,
他们就解决了他
they came after him.
这就能解释那场争吵了
That would explain the argument.
-埃斯波西托  -我们都不知道有没有那场争吵
- Esposito. - We don't even know that there was an argument,
我们唯一的证据就是布丽吉特声称
and the only evidence we have is a sketch of a man
她看到的男人的画像
that Bridget claims she saw.
好的  谢了
All right, thanks.
警员们到扎克家了
Uniforms just got to Zack's place.
那看起来像被扫荡过一样
Looks like it's been tossed.
这里就像我的第一个公寓
This place looks like my first apartment.
我们还举行过蟑螂赛跑
We used to have cockroach races.
不知道卡夫卡的灵感是否来自于此
Wonder if that's how Kafka got the idea.
看来扎克并不做家务啊
Looks like Zack didn't do his chores.
扎克遇害接着他家就被翻过
Zack was killed and then his place gets trashed?
这绝不是巧合
Not a coincidence.
你觉得这和讨债有关系吗
You think maybe this was part of a debt collection effort?
那怎么没把电视机和笔记本电脑带走
Well, then why'd they leave the tv and the laptop?
或者医疗器械
Or the medical supplies.
剔牙钳
Dental pick.
你觉得齿菌斑会让你游不快吗
You think plaque slows you down in the water?
他们是有目的性的翻找
They were looking for something specific.
除非其他地方都找过了
You don't rip through a mattress
否则不会还把床垫扯开来找
unless you've run out of places to look.
他们可能没找到想要的东西
Maybe they didn't find what they were looking for.
那东西可能还在这  只是藏得太好了
Maybe it's still here, but it's just too well hidden.
怎么了
What?
药物吗
Medication?
就我所知  只有一样东西
Only one thing I know of
是装在这种管形瓶里的
comes in little vials like that.
合成代谢类固醇
Anabolic steroids.
扎克没有服药
Zack's clean.
他怎么会有类固醇呢
Why would he have steroids?
也许他没有我们想象的那么干净
Maybe he's not as clean as we thought.
翻译：米苏   旺妹   媛媛   DJ   落末一地   LyraL   思无邪   Irene
时间轴：小穗   好油油    校对：大卫熊   后期&总监：瓜瓜
是类固醇没错
Yep, it's steroids all right.
我记得你说过扎克并没有服用类固醇
I thought you said Zack wasn't using steroids.
-测试检测不出来这个  -为什么
- The test wouldn't pick up stuff like this. - Why not?
它里面含有掩蔽剂就是为躲过测试
It's loaded with masking agents and designed to beat the test--
几乎找不到  除非你特意检测
virtually untraceable unless you look for it specifically.
-所以他有服用这个  -没有
- So he was using. - Nope.
我也针对这个做了测试
I went back and tested for this, too.
他没在服用任何类固醇
Your boy is steroid-free.
如果他不用
Well, if he wasn't using steroids,
那怎么会有这些类固醇
then what was he doing with them?
几乎检测不到吗
Virtually undetectable?
这种药都哪来的
Where does a drug like that come from?
有传言说
There's been some talk about
有种来自东欧某处的新药
a new beat-the-test performance-enhancing drug
能让人成绩提升而且检验不出来
being developed somewhere in eastern Europe.
东欧...
Eastern Europe...
口音不明者的故乡
Home of the hard-to-identify accent.
想想大家都说扎克很优秀
Given how great everyone says Zack was,
这些类固醇的存在说不通啊
this whole steroids thing just doesn't make sense.
他需要钱
Well, we know he needed the money.
如果他不用  就是拿来卖
If he wasn't using, maybe he was dealing.
这些肯定能给他足够的现金
Well, that definitely would've given him the cash needed
维持收支平衡
to make ends meet.
可他只有这么一点
Yeah, but he only had a couple of vials.
也许他现在是存货偏低的时候
Maybe he was low on inventory,
和扎克争吵的那个男人
and the man Zack was arguing with,
我们神秘的斯拉夫人是个分销商
our secretive Slav, he was the distributor.
前提是那男人真的存在
If there even was a man.
据我们所知  布丽吉特在说谎
For all we know, Bridget was lying.
关于她兄弟  她说的是实话
Well, she wasn't lying about her brothers.
我和他们四个谈过了
I talked to all four of them,
爱尔兰裔男人间的交谈
one Irishman to another and another.
总之  他们的不在场证明都成立
Anyway, they alibied out.
扎克遇害的时候他们在新帕尔茨
They were in New Paltz when Zack was killed.
-全部吗  -没错
- All of them? - Mm-hmm.
在那干嘛
For what?
他们在参加某种运动
They were at a sporting event of a... sorts.
这种运动是...
Which was?
小矮妖投掷游戏  别问了
Leprechaun toss. Don't ask.
反正  年长的得了第一
Anyway, the, uh, older brother, he got first place.
老天...
Oh, man.
暂且不去吐槽爱尔兰文化的优点...
Well, the merits of Irish culture aside...
-喂  -抱歉
- Hey! - Sorry.
或许这说明了关于神秘的爱沙尼亚人
Perhaps this suggests that Bridget was telling the truth
布丽吉特说的是实话
about our elusive Estonian.
我把素描图传给缉毒组和扫黄组
I'll run the sketch past narco and vice,
看是否有人认出他
see if they recognize him.
再看看他们是否在留意扎克
Okay, and check if Zack was on their radar.
埃斯波西托  你和扎克的队友们谈下
And, Esposito, can you talk to Zack's teammates
类固醇的事  看看他们知道些什么
about the steroids, find out what they knew?
扎克不会碰类固醇
Zack would never touch steroids.
我们都不会这么做
None of us would.
事实是
Look, the fact of the matter is,
扎克没在用
Zack was clean,
可我们在他房间找到了类固醇
but we found steroids at his place.
我们只想知道为什么
We're just trying to figure out why.
你是在说扎克卖那些东西吗
Are you saying you think Zack was a dealer?
他死了还不够
Look, it's not enough that he's dead.
你还打算给他抹黑吗
Now you gotta drag him through the mud?
我给你说说扎克·林赛好了
Let me tell you something about Zack Lindsey.
他是这个队伍的核心和灵魂人物
He was the heart and soul of this team.
是我们的榜样
He was the person we wanted to be.
如果你有发现药物  肯定是别的原因
So if you found drugs, they were there for another reason.
不管什么理由  他肯定图谋不轨
Whatever the reason, he was up to something.
他三个邻居说
Statements from three of his neighbors say that
他外出后彻夜不归
he was going out and staying out all night.
是去游泳池训练  这是我们已知的事实
Yes, to the pool to train. We already know that.
但有一半时间  他没带运动包就出门了
Except half the time, he was leaving without his gym bag,
那他是去哪儿了
so where was he going?
我希望你是已经有了答案
I'm hoping that you're asking that just for effect
为做效果才这么问的
because you already have an answer.
我不知道
I-I got nothing.
也许你查错了方向
Maybe you're looking at it wrong.
类固醇可能和这起谋杀没关系
Maybe the steroids have nothing to do with his murder.
它们只是在干扰你的调查方向
Maybe they're your red herring.
艾利克斯  你来了我很高兴
Alex, so glad you made it.
艾利克斯·康拉德  来见见贝克特探长
Alex Conrad, please meet Detective Beckett.
贝克特探长  这位是我门生艾利克斯·康拉德
Detective Beckett, Alex Conrad, my protégé.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
是我的荣幸才对  探长
It's a real pleasure, detective.
我读过好多次《希特热浪》和《赤裸热浪》
I have read "Heat wave" And "Naked heat" so many times,
觉得自己很了解你...
I feel like I know you--
你的聪明才智  美丽自信
the piercing intelligence, the self-assured beauty.
谢谢你的称赞
Oh, um, thank you.
你刚说类固醇什么
Uh, so what were you saying about the steroids?
没什么特别的
Well, nothing really.
我只是看着白板  注意到
I was just looking at the board, and I noticed
这游泳的孩子和类固醇  仿佛是两个世界的事
that this swimmer kid, he's caught between two worlds.
如果是在写小说
Now if were writing the story,
类固醇是用来分散注意力的
the steroids would just be a red herring,
而真正的凶手
and the real killer
是以前的街坊邻居
would be someone from the old neighborhood.
但这只是我的想法
Uh, yeah. But, hey, that's just me.
在这方面我还是个新手
Clearly I'm new at this.
别担心  艾利克斯  这需要时间来积累经验
Alex, don't worry. It takes years of experience--
不会  你是对的  我们没有证据
No. No, you're right. We don't have any proof
把他和类固醇联系起来
that his has anything to do with the steroids.
这一切都是我们的假设
We've just been assuming.
我们的确也要深入了解下扎克的街坊邻居
We do need to look into zack's old neighborhood as well.
你说真的  我帮上忙了吗
Seriously? I was helpful?
是啊  你帮上忙了
Yes. Yes, you were.
是的  你大概有很多问题吧
Yes, but you probably have lots of questions,
所以我们该走了
so we should get going.
如果这样不会越界的话
Hey, uh, if it's not overstepping,
就是为了让我的描写贴近现实  我在想
just in the interest of keeping it real, I was wondering
能问你几个问题吗
if I could ask you a few questions
是为了我《必死无疑》里的案子
for the case I'm coming up with for "Seriously Dead".
等你们俩谈完了
Why don't you just give me a buzz
给我打电话吧
when the two of you are done?
-要是你不介意的话  -怎么会呢
- I mean, if it's okay with you. - Why wouldn't it be okay?
-好的  -好的
- Okay. - Okay.
一点都不好  我为他做了那么多
It's so not okay. After everything I've done for him,
他却要偷走我的缪斯
he goes and tries to steal my Muse.
盗窃缪斯罪  怎么惩戒这样的罪恶呢
Muse thievery. What's the punishment for that,
在神话监狱关他个五到十年吗
five to ten in mythology jail?
你们就笑吧
Yes, you laugh.
笑吧  尽情地笑吧
Go ahead. Laugh all you want.
不过我现在终于能体会欧比旺·肯诺比
But now I finally know what Obi-Wan Kenobi felt like
发现黑武士背叛他时的心情了
when Darth Vader turned on him.
我该预料到的  你知道黑卒
I shoulda seen this coming. You know what
-出版社叫他什么吗  -不知道
- they're calling him down at Black Pawn Publishing? -No.
-艾利克斯·康拉德  -"下一个理查德·卡塞尔"
- Alex Conrad? - "The next Richard Castle."
-天啊  -可不是嘛
- Oh. - Yes.
我还以为是对我的褒扬呢  才不是呢
I thought it was a compliment, but, no.
-他是想取代我  -你要干嘛呀
- He's trying to replace me. - What are you gonna do?
我要上理查德·卡塞尔个人网站
I am going on to richardcastle.net,
把我对《千真万确》的溢美之词撤下来
I am going to remove my glowing review of "Dead Serious",
换成《希特崛起》的封面
and replace it with cover art for "Heat Rises".
-那个忘恩负义龌龊小人  -老爸  你不觉得
- That ungrateful little weasel... - Dad, you ever think
你有点反应过激了吗
that maybe you're overreacting a teensy bit?
你有没有想过他可能是太崇拜你了
You ever think that maybe he admires you so much
跟贝克特在一起也是为了进一步了解你呢
that spending time with Beckett is to understand you better?
别用你的理性来扰乱我
Don't confuse me with your reasonableness.
我就是想说
I'm just saying...
或许他不是你想的那种穷凶极恶夺人缪斯的人
maybe he's not the nefarious Muse-snatcher you think he is.
或许你该给人家个机会
Maybe you should give him a chance.
或许
Maybe...
你是对的
you're right.
好的  谢谢你的配合
Okay, great. Thank you for your cooperation.
谢谢
Thank you.
布丽吉特·麦克马尼斯说
So Bridget McManus says that
扎克早就不跟本森赫斯特那帮人混了
Zack didn't really run with the Bensonhurst crowd anymore,
不过她给了我一份名单
but she did give me a list
列出了他以前所有邻居伙伴
of all of his old neighborhood buddies.
-我来查查吧  -好呀
- Oh, how about I run it down? - Yeah, great.
好
Yeah.
小松糕啊
Muffins.
艾利克斯·康拉德送给我的
Alex Conrad sent them to me.
艾利克斯
Alex.
"昨晚的事多谢了"
"Thanks for last night."
那么说你们俩昨晚小聚了
Guess you two got together last night.
是啊  我们谈了有关办案程序的问题
Yeah, we talked about procedure.
那就是  没什么特别的事了
Oh, so... nothing special.
说不准
I don't know.
他说会把学到的用在他下一本书里
He said he was gonna use it all for his next book,
-还说下次想谈谈案子  -还有下次
- said next time he wants to talk about cases. - Next time?
我查到一些被害人的事情
So something came up on our victim.
-不知道该怎么解释  -是关于类固醇的吗
- Not sure what to make of it. - About steroids?
-不是  -是关于那神秘的摩尔达维亚人吗
- No. - About our mysterious Moldavian?
不  也不是
No, not that either.
扫黄组和缉毒组均没留意过扎克和东欧男
Vice and narcotics struck out on Zack and the sketch.
但是我在悬案资料库里
But I ran Zack's fingerprints
比对了扎克的指纹
through the unsolved latent database.
他的指纹跟两周前
His prints match a set
在皇后区失窃的一辆车上找到的相匹配
found on a car stolen in Queens two weeks ago.
车是谁的
Who's the owner?
一位叫派翠西·法莱尔的
A Patricia Farrell.
没印象
Name doesn't ring a bell.
我想我知道这是干嘛的了
I think I know... what these are about.
我看到过一段录像
It's, um, a video I saw
是前段时间在一个地下网站上看到的
on an underground web site a while ago.
不奇怪啊
Not surprising.
就看着吧
Just watch.
这里
Here.
扎克不工作也能赚到学费和房租
So that's how Zack made tuition and rent
-靠的是这个  -扎克可是有工作的
- all without a job. - Oh, Zack had a job all right.
他是偷车贼
He was a car thief.
现在我们知道扎克是怎么赚钱的了
Now we know how Zack made his money,
还有他晚上为什么出去  他是
why he was out all night... he was
-去玩"侠盗猎车手"了  -还是现实版的
- playing "Grand Theft Auto." - Yeah, the live-action version.
或许他是偷了不该偷的车
Maybe he boosted the wrong car and got in trouble
结果跟他的"同事"起了摩擦
with the people he was working with.
或许是那位"要命"的立陶宛人
Our lethal Lithuanian, perhaps?
猜错了  老弟
Guess again, bro.
我查过扎克那些本森赫斯特的朋友
I ran the names of Zack's pals from Bensonhurst.
有一个人有偷车的前科的  叫托马斯·马克恩
One of them has a prior for auto theft, a Thomas Marcone.
汤米·马克恩  布丽吉特说那是
Tommy Marcone? Bridget said that
扎克高中时最好的朋友
that was zack's best friend in high school.
很多偷车贼都是成双作案的
Lots of car thieves run in pairs.
我们去一趟本森赫斯特吧
Let's go to Bensonhurst.
就是那里斯卡伦酒吧
That's it. Scanlon's bar,
汤米·马克恩常在那里闲晃
Tommy Marcone's unofficial hangout.
看起来这儿的人在为他们的英雄哀悼啊
Looks like the neighborhood is mourning their local hero.
是啊  不过我现在不确定他还是不是英雄
Yeah, well, at this point, I'm not sure that's what he was.
生于逆境
Man born into hardship
努力上进
struggles to reach for something greater,
却躲不过往日的阴影
only he can't escape the demons of his past.
这是"俄狄浦斯"  是《教父》
It's "Oedipus," it's "The Godfather,"
《贝弗利山人》
"The Beverly Hillbillies".
不至于那么好笑吧
It wasn't that funny.
不是  抱歉  我刚收到一条短信
No, I'm sorry. I just got a message.
谁发来的  康拉德吗  是不是  他说什么
From who? Conrad? It is, isn't it? What did he say?
没什么  他就是问问
Nothing. He just wants to know what
-今晚什么时候见  -这就能把你逗笑
- time I can meet up tonight. - And that made you laugh?
是啊  他很幽默
Yeah. He's funny.
汤米·马克恩
Tommy Marcone.
纽约警局
NYPD.
你们找错人了
You got the wrong guy.
记得这个吗
Remember when?
你还在假释期  是吧
You're still on probation, aren't you?
我有几个关于扎克·林赛谋杀案的问题要问
Got a couple of questions about Zack Lindsey's murder.
你为何要在整个酒吧的人面前审我啊
Why you gotta sweat me in front of the whole bar?
那你想我怎么做  带你回局里吗
What do you want me to do, take you downtown?
我知道你们两个
I know that the two of you
-曾一起偷车  -你没有证据
- were stealing cars together. - You can't prove that.
我知道你们俩是朋友
I know that the two of you were friends,
我知道我在一辆被盗的车上查到扎克的指纹
I know that I've got Zack's prints on a stolen car,
我还知道你有前科
and I also know that you have priors.
既然你们俩是朋友  我们就想
And since you two are friends, we thought
或许你不会对扎克的死无动于衷
maybe you'd care that Zack's laying on a slab
会想要帮帮他
and thought you might want to help him.
他死了  我帮不上什么忙
He's dead. Ain't nothing I can do now.
你干嘛不说说你谋杀当日
Why don't you tell me where you were
凌晨1点到5点在哪
between 1:00 and 5:00 a.m. the night of the murder?
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
你见过这个男人吗
You ever see this man?
没有  你的手表对一个警察来说太贵了
No, and your watch is too expensive for a cop's.
那么探长  这家伙是谁
So, detective, who's this guy?
他是为在座所有人买单的人
He's the guy buying a round for the house.
汤米  如果你知道什么  你应该告诉我
Tommy, if you know something, you should talk.
各位  这轮酒我请客
Hey, everybody, a round for the house.
以此纪念扎克·林赛
In memory of Zack Lindsey.
扎克是个好孩子
Zack was a great kid.
这里所有人都很喜欢他
Everybody around here loved him,
包括汤米
Tommy included.
素描上的人
well, the guy in the sketch
肯定是吉米·伦农
is definitely Jimmy Lennon--
重大盗窃车辆罪
Grand theft auto,
密谋倒卖偷来的车辆
conspiracy to sell stolen vehicles,
侵犯人身罪  使用致命性武器袭击他人
assault, assault with a deadly weapon.
28岁时移民至美国
He immigrated to the U.S. when he was 28.
但是他出生于白俄罗斯明斯克的
But he was born Janusz Lenadovsky
亚努斯兰纳戴夫斯基
in Minsk, Belarus.
白俄罗斯  我知道  就在立陶宛旁边
Belarus. I knew it. That's right next to Lithuania.
这上面写着他在U大街拥有一家汽车修理店
It says here that he owns an auto repair shop on Avenue U.
当心点  这家伙很危险
Watch your backs on this one. This guy is dangerous.
那里
There.
吉米·伦农
Jimmy Lennon.
纽约...站住
NYP--hey!
将其他人抓起来  给汽车盗窃组打电话
Round up the others. Call burglary auto.
纽约警局
Hey! Hey! NYPD!
这是合法生意  我是修车的
This is clean business. I fix these cars.
真的吗
Really?
我打赌车主听到这话会非常吃惊的
I bet the people who own them would be surprised to hear that.
现在我想知道有关扎克·林赛的事
Now I want to know about Zack Lindsey.
我什么也不知道
I know not.
从你嘴里说出的并不是
Not the best three words to have
我最想听到的话  吉米
falling out of your mouth, Jimmy.
我本期待他会说麋鹿和松鼠呢
I was half expecting "Moose" and "Squirrel".
你会进监狱的  待多久就取决于你了
You're going to jail. How long depends on you.
你们国家的监狱就像度假村
Jail in your country is vacation.
我会让它变成最烂的度假村
Then I will make it very difficult.
我是这么想的  我认为扎克为你偷车
Here's what I think--I think that Zack stole cars for you.
但他有更好的打算  他告诉你他不想干了
But he had bigger plans, and he told you he wanted out.
你担心他会告诉别人
You were worried he couldn't keep his mouth shut,
所以你就威胁他
so you threatened him
告诉他不能退出
and told him, there's no walking outta this.
他还是没改变主意  你就跟踪他
And when he didn't change his mind, you followed him
来到泳池边  然后杀了他
to the pool and you killed him.
还有什么需要补充的吗
Is there anything you want to add to that?
你要好自为之  吉米  这是你最后的机会
You should help yourself, Jimmy. This is your last chance.
为金牌而游
Swim for gold.
什么
What?
那边有辆车
There's a car over there
车牌是SWM4GLD
with the license plate "SWM4GLD."
这辆车注册在康涅狄格州格林威治镇
This car is registered to a Brian Morris
布莱恩·莫里斯名下
Of Greenwich, Connecticut.
布莱恩·莫里斯  那是扎克的一名队友
Brian Morris. That's one of Zack's teammates.
那是他主要的竞争对手
That's his main rival.
那么要么是布莱恩的引擎需要翻新了
So either Brian needed his engine rebuilt or...
要么就是这辆车被偷了
Or this car is stolen.
扎克为什么要偷布莱恩的车呢
So why would Zack steal Brian's car?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是我知道布莱恩为什么有谋杀动机了
But I know why it gave brian a motive for murder.
我们在扎克公寓发现的类固醇
Those steroids we found in Zack's apartment...
他没服用的那些
that he wasn't taking
也许是布莱恩的
maybe they're Brian's.
为什么让我来这里  我没做什么坏事
Why you got me in here? I didn't do nothin' wrong.
没做吗  扎克在游泳队的竞争对手
No? Zack's rival on the swim team,
布莱恩·莫里斯
Brian Morris.
我们在地下拆车厂发现了他的克尔维特跑车
We found his sting Ray at the chop shop--
你偷走的那辆
the one you stole.
我都不知道那是什么意思
I don't even know what that means.
车上有扎克的指纹  也有你的
Zack's prints were on it, and so were yours.
所以别装了
So stop playing around.
你们为什么偷那辆车
Why did you boost the car?
因为布莱恩·莫里斯是一个装逼的富二代
Because Brian Morris is a silver-spoon-licking punk.
他恨扎克  因为扎克比他游得更好
He hated Zack for being a better swimmer.
两周前  他在扎克赛前餐里
Two weeks ago, he spiked Zack's pregame meal
偷偷下了药让他生病
to make him sick.
扎克还是赢了比赛
Zack won the meet anyway.
没多久他就知道是布莱恩搞的鬼
Didn't take him long to figure out it was Brian, though.
你们偷那辆车是为了报复
So you took the car out of revenge?
"为金牌而游"  那种虚荣牌照
"SWM4GLD" vanity plates--
要不要再土鳖一点啊
I mean, can you get any more douchey?
布莱恩在格林威治有自己的训练泳池
Brian's up in Greenwich with his own training pool,
私人教练  应有尽有
private coaches, whatever he needs.
而扎克却被困在这里
Meanwhile Zack's stuck here,
偷车就是为了混口饭吃
boosting cars just so he can eat.
因为他不能拿别人的钱
'Cause he can't take a nickel of outside money
拿了他就完了
or else he's done.
你们是怎么找到类固醇的
How did you find the steroids?
一定要检查车子
You always search a car.
永远不要招惹自己招惹不起的
You never want more than you bargained for.
比如后车厢里死掉的黑手党吗
Like a dead mobster in the trunk?
那种事常有
That stuff happens.
我们像往常一样检查那辆车
We searched the car like always,
扎克在车坐垫下面发现了一个包
Zack found a bag underneath the seat,
他当场就明白了  布莱恩在用药
and he knew right then and there, Brian was juicing.
扎克对这个发现有什么打算吗
Did Zack have any plans for this information?
他还没想好  这可是件大事
He hadn't figured that out yet. Kind of a big deal, you know?
我说他应该举报那个作弊的混蛋布莱恩
I told him he should turn that cheating bastard Brian in,
让他禁赛
get his ass banned.
我猜他没得到机会
Guess he never got the chance.
是啊
I guess not.
扎克是你最好的朋友  汤米
Zack was supposed to be your friend, tommy.
为什么你一开始不告诉我们这些
Why didn't you tell us this from the start?
我不知道  也许
I don't know. Maybe...
我太害怕了
I was scared.
好吧  别出城
All right. Stick around.
我还会找你
I'm not done with you.
你认识这个吗  布莱恩
You recognize this, Brian?
探长  如果一开始就是对抗式审判
If it's gonna be adversarial from the outset, detective...
用这个作为对抗式审判怎么样  律师
How's this for adversarial, counselor?
扎克·林赛在发现你委托人车上违法的
Zack Lindsey was killed after he found
类固醇后就被杀死了
a cache of illegal steroids in your client's car.
一辆显然是他偷走的车
A car he apparently stole.
奇怪的是  你儿子从来没有举报过
And oddly enough, your son never, ever reported it...
她在那就像只老虎
She's like a tiger in there.
我永远都看不腻她
I never get tired of watching her.
我也是
Me neither.
貌似艾利克斯·康拉德也这么想
Seems like Alex Conrad feels the same way.
一辆价值超过七万的古董车不见了
A classic car worth over 70 grand goes missing,
而你却告诉我你不知道它不见了
and you're telling me that you had no idea it was gone?
我怎么会知道  我几乎没开过它
Why would I? I... I barely even drive it.
你知道那车被偷了
You knew that car was stolen.
你不想要警察找到它
You didn't want police to recover it.
以免他们找到更多的这些
In case they found more of these.
你没有证据
You have no proof of that.
扎克可能是将类固醇栽赃到布莱恩车上
Zack could've planted steroids in Brian's car.
但是他没有
But he didn't.
我认为扎克因为那些类固醇
You know, I think that Zack confronted you
而去找你当面对质
about those steroids.
而你知道一旦他举报了你  你就要
And you knew if he reported you, you could
和你的奥林匹克梦说再见了  于是你杀了他
kiss your Olympic dreams good-bye, and so you killed him.
布莱恩  你杀了扎克
Brian, you killed Zack.
然后你就闯入他的公寓
And then you broke into his apartment
试图销毁你的罪证
and tried to cover your tracks.
据我回忆
To my recollection,
扎克·林赛和我绝对没有讨论过
at no point did Zack Lindsey and I discuss
任何有关兴奋剂的事
any performance-enhancing substance.
而且我也不知道是谁杀了他
And I have no idea who killed him.
布莱恩  你的表现可配不上金牌
Not a gold medal performance, Brian.
案发当晚的凌晨1点至5点
Where were you between 1:00 and 5:00 a.m.
你在哪里
the night of the murder?
我都说过多少遍了
We've been over all this.
我在父母家的游泳池练习
I was at the practice pool at my parents' house.
这张影碟是安在训练池上方的摄像机拍下的
This DVD is from a camera mounted above the training pool.
上面有时间和日期
It has the date and time running in the corner.
太容易伪造了
Easily altered.
此外  莫里斯家族和其员工都担保
Furthermore, the Morris family and staff all swear
布莱恩那天在家  我有书面证词
Brian was at home, and I have affidavits.
你肯定有
I'm sure you do.
除非你要起诉我的当事人
So unless you're charging my client,
否则我们告辞了
we're done here.
我儿子一定会参加奥运会
My son will go to the Olympics,
谁也别想阻拦  探长
and no one's going to derail that, detective.
布莱恩有作案手段  有作案动机
Brian had means, he had motive.
满足了这两条
That's at least two.
那他作案的时机呢
What about opportunity?
很明显  他父亲会不惜一切代价
Clearly, his father would do whatever it takes
为他掩护  好让他能继续游泳
to cover for him so he can keep on swimming.
布莱恩有这样的团队支持
Well, with the kind of team Brian had, there's no way
我们根本找不到证据
we'll be able to prove
证明他在大学泳池出现过
that he was at the U.N.Y. Pool.
也许他真的没出现过
Maybe because he wasn't.
看看布莱恩这类人
Look what kind of guy Brian is--pampered,
被他父亲娇惯  保护和操控着
protected, dominated by his father.
他可不是"实干家"
This is not a man of action.
那你的意思是
So what are you suggesting?
他不会脏了自己的手
That he's not the kind of guy to get his hands dirty.
也许有老爸为他善后
Maybe daddy cleaned up his mess.
或者是买凶杀人
Or he hired someone to do it for him.
莱恩  你能查到莫里斯家族的财务状况吗
Ryan, can you look into the Morris' financials?
查查案发前后有没有什么大额付款
Look for large payments made around the time of the murder,
尤其是现金支取
especially cash withdrawals.
已经查了
Already on it.
老爸是一个对冲基金经理
The dad is a Hedge Fund Manager,
要查他的财务  得找个工商管理学硕士
so you practically need an MBA to follow the money.
但是孩子这有线索
But there was something about the kid.
有一笔担保的钱
There was a bond.
是保释金吗
As in bail bond?
是储蓄金
As in savings bond.
在布莱恩的车被盗后三天
Three days after Brian's car was stolen,
他从储蓄金里提现2万5千元美金
he cashed in a savings bond in the amount of $25,000.
足够雇个职业杀手了
That's enough to hire a hit man.
尤其在当今这个竞争激烈的求职市场
Especially in today's competitive job market.
布莱恩是从格林威治联邦银行里提现的吗
Did Brian Morris cash that bond at Greenwich Federal Bank?
是啊  你发现了什么
Matter of fact, he did. What do you got?
我们刚刚搜了托马斯·马克恩的住所
We just searched Thomas Marcone's place.
发现了一些偷车工具
Found tools of the auto theft trade.
还有这个
But we also found this.
看起来差不多有2万5美元
That looks like 25 grand.
猜猜是哪来的
And guess where it's from.
格林威治联邦银行
Greenwich Federal Bank.
扎克不是我杀的
I didn't kill Zack.
汤米  似乎你每开一次口
Tommy, it seems like every time
就有一个新的谎言跑出来
you open your mouth, another lie falls out.
我没说谎
But I'm not lying.
那你为什么收了布莱恩·莫里斯的2万5千块
Then why did you take 25 grand from Brian Morris?
据我回忆  你管这个人叫
A man you characterized as a "cheating bastard,"
"作弊的混蛋"
as I recall.
好吧  也许扎克的死是因为我
Okay, I may have gotten Zack killed,
但不是你们想的那样
but not the way you think.
是勒索
It was blackmail.
你勒索了布莱恩·莫里斯
You blackmailed Brian Morris.
他一直在用类固醇
Him being on steroids--
我觉得这个信息很有价值
Yeah, I figured that knowledge was worth something.
扎克参与了吗
Was Zack in on this?
他要是知道了会把我
He woulda kicked my ass
一直踢到第18大街的
up and down 18th Avenue if he found out.
踢你也是你活该
And been justified.
布莱恩不认识我  我认为
Look, Brian didn't know me, and I figured, he wouldn't pay
他不会把钱给一个匿名勒索的家伙
if he got blackmailed by some anonymous mook.
所以你就假扮成扎克
So you pretended to be Zack.
我用图书馆的电脑登陆了扎克的邮箱
I used the library computer and Zack's e-mail account.
给布莱恩发了封电邮
I emailed Brian
说我拿到了他的类固醇
saying I had his 'roids
说我要举报他
and I was gonna rat him out
除非他用纸袋装2万5千块
unless he put 25 grand into a paper bag
放在方院的长椅下面
and left it underneath a bench at the quad.
等周围没人的时候  我把钱拿走
When the coast was clear, I picked it up.
我无意伤害任何人
I never meant for anyone to get hurt.
我想打个电话
I'd like that phone call now.
扎克偷了布莱恩的车
Okay, so Zack stole Brian's stash
但由于汤米
and because of Tommy,
布莱恩以为是扎克在勒索他
Brian thought that Zack... was blackmailing him.
布莱恩的杀人动机真是越来越强烈了
Brian's motive just keeps getting stronger and stronger.
就像打了类固醇一样
Almost like it's on steroids.
-蒂诺威女士  -汤米·马克恩打电话
- Ms. Dinovi. - Tommy Marcone called,
说你们把他抓这来了
said you have him in here.
他还说是布莱恩·莫里斯杀了我儿子
He said Brian Morris killed my son.
还不确定
We don't know all that.
他只是有嫌疑而已
We just know he's a person of interest.
那你们为什么不拘捕他
So why didn't you arrest him?
我们没有足够的证据扣留他
We don't have enough to hold him.
还因为他是富翁的儿子
And he's the son of a millionaire.
肯定跟这个脱不了关系
I bet that doesn't hurt either.
在这里  讲求的是证据
Around here, it's about the evidence,
而不是谁的钱包有多厚
not how fat someone's wallet is.
我活在现实世界里
Yeah, well, I live in the real world,
我知道那男孩的家庭背景
and I know that boy's family,
他们定会不惜一切代价去保护他
and they're gonna do whatever it takes to protect him
因为他们有这个能力
because they can.
队长  扎克是我的全部
Captain... Zack's all I had.
除非我们找到真凶  否则无法确定
We can't figure out if Brian is connected to the murder
布莱恩是否跟本案有直接联系
until we find the real killer.
那你们就加把劲
Then you're gonna have to dig deeper.
如果布莱恩和他的家人参与了本案
If Brian and his family are involved, then there's
那其中必然有某种联系
gotta be a connection,
给我找出来
and I want it found.
好  谢谢
All right, great. Thank you.
这个线索也断了
We struck out again.
莫里斯家在康州的房子
The Morris' house in Connecticut
大门有警卫  保安公司说
is gated, and the security company says
案发当晚没有任何人外出
that nobody left the night of the murder.
他们的证供滴水不漏
These guys have everything covered.
什么
What?
扎克的邮箱账号
Zack's e-mail account,
就是汤米用来勒索布莱恩的那个
the one Tommy used to ask Brian for a donation?
勒索信是下午3点零2分发出去的
The blackmail message was sent at 3:02 p.m.
你会以为那会引发布莱恩打很多电话吧
You'd think that would've caused a flurry of telephone calls.
但他只在3点19分后打了一通电话
But he only made one call right after--3:19.
是他父亲纽约的办公室电话
That's the father's office in New York.
有老爸的通话记录吗
Do we have the dad's records?
我这有  从下午3点21分开始
Yeah, I got it right here. Starting at 3:21 p.m.,
本杰明·莫里斯打了数十通电话
Benjamin Morris made about a dozen phone calls,
全都拨的是2-1-2这个号码
all to the same 2-1-2 number.
查查
Run it.
是雷克斯·克拉伯医生的电话
It's a Dr. Rex Colabro.
他是从事运动医学行业的
He's got a sports medicine practice.
有好多一流运动员都是他的客户
He's got a lot of big-time athletes as clients.
那么本杰明·莫里斯发现
So Benjamin Morris finds out
他的儿子被人勒索了
that his son is being blackmailed,
却打电话给了克拉伯医生
and the one phone call he makes is to Dr. Colabro?
只有一个理由说得通
The only reason that that would make sense is if...
克拉伯医生知道类固醇的事
Dr. Colabro knew about the steroids,
说不定还是他提供的
maybe even supplied them.
我没向任何人提供过类固醇
I don't supply steroids to anyone.
从没有  也绝不会
Never have. Never will.
我见过类固醇所造成的长期伤害
I've seen the long-term damage they cause.
在我看来  这玩意是毒药
As far as I'm concerned, the stuff's poison.
那布莱恩·莫里斯呢
And what about Brian Morris?
他是你的病人吗
Is he a patient of yours?
这是保密资料
That's confidential information.
他父亲星期二在两小时内给你打了七通电话
His father called you seven times in a 2-hour period on Tuesday.
你们聊了什么
What did the two of you talk about?
这也是保密资料
That's confidential as well.
克拉伯医生  你的客户
Dr. Colabro, your clientele
主要是知名运动员
is mostly high-profile athletes.
你觉得一旦他们发现你跟我们谈过
How fast do you think they'll abandon ship
类固醇的事  会多快对你弃之不用呢
once they find out you're talking with us about steroids?
我猜会很快
I'm guessing fast.
而当他们发现谈的是类固醇和谋杀
And when they find out it's steroids and murder,
会以光速飞奔
it'll jump to lightspeed.
谋杀  你觉得我卷入了谋杀吗
Murder? You think I'm mixed up in a murder?
我觉得为了你自己考虑  最好帮助我们
I think that it would be in your best interest to help us.
告诉我们本杰明·莫里斯
Tell us what you and
-和你聊了什么  -而事实上
- Benjamin Morris talked about. - And point of fact...
布莱恩是你的病人
Brian was your patient,
但我想他父亲不是
but I'm guessing his father was not.
因此不适用于保密条例
So confidentiality really doesn't apply.
这样如何
How's this?
假设来说
Hypothetically...
一个类固醇使用者的专横父亲
Why would an overbearing father of
为什么会给你打电话
a steroid-using swimmer call you?
假设来说
"Hypothetically"...
他可能是问某种违禁药
He might have asked how long a certain banned drug
在某人的身体里会残留多久
would remain detectable in someone's system.
担心他儿子的药检呈阳性
Worried his son would test positive.
还可能聊了什么呢
And what else might have come up?
运动员避免药检的方法
That the way an athlete can avoid testing
是他因受伤而临时退出该项运动
is if he's injured and temporarily withdraws from the sport.
假设而已
Hypothetically.
我去申请搜查证
I'll get a warrant,
看看克拉伯的办公室里有没有类固醇
check Colabro's office for steroids.
不可能有
You won't find any.
本杰明打电话来合谋对策
Benjamin called in to concoct a strategy
以保住布莱恩的参赛资格
to protect Brian's eligibility.
这是损害控制  不是谋杀
This is damage control not murder.
看来这对策已付诸实施了
Well, it looks like the strategy has been put into effect.
布莱恩以肩膀受伤为由退出游泳队
Brian quit the swim team, said he injured his shoulder.
不在游泳队  就不用药检
No swim team, no drug testing.
我把蕾妮关于类固醇的报告
So I checked Lanie's report on the steroids
与从缉毒组拿到的资料做了对比
against the file I got from vice.
发现缉毒组拦截过一批相似的类固醇
They intercepted a shipment of similar steroids
是从罗马尼亚的一个实验室运往纽约的
that came to New York from a lab in Romania.
查下布莱恩的生活圈子
So let's look into Brian's life,
看看是否与罗马尼亚有任何联系
see if there's any connection to Romania.
如果能找到点联系  也许就能
If we can find a connect, then hopefully
找到杀死扎克的凶手
we'll be able to find Zack's killer.
凯特  可以走了吗
Kate, you ready?
是啊  等我去拿包
Yeah. Um, let me just go get my purse.
你们今晚又要出去吗
You guys are going out again tonight?
我还能说什么呢  她让人灵感不断
What can I say? She's a wealth of information.
有她你真幸运
You are lucky to have her.
是啊  我是幸运
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
但今晚还是太遗憾了
Too bad about tonight, though.
怎么太遗憾
Too bad how?
今晚是扑克之夜
Well, it's poker night.
雷恩和康纳利来了
Lehane and Connelly are in town.
本想你若没其他安排的话
I thought you might want to join us,
就跟我一起去
but if you have plans.
不会吧  你是在邀请我
No way. You're-- you're inviting me
参加你们悬疑作家的扑克之夜吗
to your mystery writers' poker night?
拜托  你现在不也是个悬疑作家了吗
Well, come on. You're a mystery writer now, right?
但那些人都是泰斗级的
Yeah, but those guys are legendary. I mean, uh--
是啊  他们是
Yeah, they are.
你没空就算了
Ah, well. If you're unavailable...
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
等等  等等
Well, wait, wait, wait.
成功
Bingo.
等我一下
Hang on a second.
没错  他们会喜欢你的
Oh, yeah. They're gonna love you.
-先生们  -这就是新来的吗
- Gentlemen. - This the new guy?
艾利克斯·康拉德
Alex Conrad,
迈克尔·康纳利  丹尼斯·雷恩
Michael Connelly, Dennis Lehane.
认识你们真是太棒了
It's really awesome to meet you guys.
我是你们的狂热粉丝
I am a, uh, huge fan.
这不是签售会  孩子  是来打牌的
It's not a book signing, kid. We're here to play poker.
对
Right.
那是坎内尔的位置
That's Cannell's seat.
有个规矩
That's the rule.
我们失去一位成员  他的位置要空一年
We lose a member, nobody sits there for a year.
对不起
Sorry.
我们刚才在聊把小说拍成电影的事
So we were just talking about our books becoming movies.
迈克尔有《林肯律师》
Michael had "Lincoln Lawyer,"
我有《禁闭岛》  里奇有《希特热浪》
I had "Shutter Island," Ricky has "Heat Wave."
你的呢  孩子
So what about your book, kid?
有要拍成电影的吗
They gonna make it into a movie?
还没有
Oh, uh, not yet.
里奇  那个死了的游泳队员怎么样了
So, Ricky, what's going on with the dead swimmer?
没什么进展  丹尼斯到你了
Treading water. Dennis, your bet.
我觉得看起来像冲动犯罪
Well, it reads like a crime of passion to me.
我打赌是他女朋友干的
I bet the girlfriend did it.
女朋友  你开玩笑的吧
The girlfriend? You're kidding, right?
五十页之前你就得结束女友这条线
You move through the girlfriend no later than page 50.
是啊  女性犯案简直是
Yeah, the woman scored is like
悬疑小说里面的陈词滥调
the oldest rodeo clown in the book.
他不是说真的吧
Is he serious?
他认真的很[卡塞尔在恶搞艾利克斯的书名]
Oh, he's "Dead Serious."
我只是想...
Well, you know, I just thought we were--
你写了多少本小说
How many books have you written?
就一本
Just the one.
而这本使你成为了破案天才  是吗
And this one book made you, like, a crime-solving genius, did it?
你知道我写完第一本小说后做了什么吗
You know what I did after I wrote my first novel?
我闭上嘴  又写了23本
I shut up and I wrote 23 more.
我告诉你  像这种案件
I can tell ya, a case like this,
有罪之人通常都是秘密最大那个
guilty party is usually the guy with the biggest secret.
丹尼斯说的对
You know, Dennis is right.
如果使用类固醇的事被曝光
Aside from Brian, who has the most to lose
除了布莱恩  谁的损失最大
if this steroid use gets out?
我突然知道是谁了
You know, I think I might just know.
真是荒唐
This is ridiculous.
那天晚上我在教练宿舍里
I was in my apartment in faculty housing that night.
你可以随便问问
You could just ask around.
我们知道那天晚上你在房间里
We know you were in your apartment that night.
那为什么还要我到这儿来
Okay. So then why am I here?
你知道这是什么吗  教练
Do you know what this is, coach?
知道  干我们这行的都知道
Uh, yeah. Everybody in my business does.
但我队里没有任何人用这玩意
But nobody on my team takes that stuff.
-布莱恩·莫里斯用了 -不可能
- Brian Morris does. - That's not true.
显然他是自己使用了类固醇
Apparently, this is his steroid of choice.
这是从罗马尼亚来的  我知道
It comes from Romania. I understand
在过去的两年内  你去过四次罗马尼亚
you've been to romania four times in the past two years.
我亲家来自布加勒斯特
My wife's family is from Bucharest.
所以你是在告诉我这只是个巧合吗
So you're trying to tell me, it's just a coincidence?
是的
Yeah.
就是说如果我搜查你的公寓和办公室
So if I search your apartment and your office,
我根本就找不到这种药瓶
you're telling me that I wouldn't find any of these vials?
你根本不明白
You don't understand.
布莱恩·莫里斯生来就是胜利者
Brian Morris was a lock to win it all.
他身体条件出众  天资过人  资金雄厚
He had the body, he had the talent, the money
这些足以成就他
to make himself the best.
他也是我来纽约大学执教的原因
He's the reason I came to coach at U.N.Y.,
但是去年  布莱恩状态下滑
But last year, Brian peaked,
开始在比赛的最后时刻掉链子
started fading at the ends of races,
然后不知道怎么的
and from outta nowhere,
扎克就成了最好的
zack became the guy to beat.
于是你就决定帮布莱恩一把
So you decided to give Brian an extra boost
让他追上扎克
so he could catch up with Zack.
布莱恩的父亲来找我
Brian's father came to me.
他问我还有什么办法
He asked if there was anything more I could do,
他说如果我给出肯定的答复
he said he'd donate millions to the program
就给项目捐款几百万
if that answer was yes.
是啊  但是这不光跟钱有关
Yeah, but it wasn't just about the money, was it?
每个教练都知道
Every coach knows,
他必须搭上一个明星才能出头
he has to hitch his wagon to a star.
事实上  你跟一个特别的人就这么干过
In fact, you'd done it before, with somebody very special.
在来纽约大学之前  你曾经在维明顿任教
Before going to U.N.Y., you were coaching in Wilmington.
对  那又如何
That's right. So?
你有没有用同样方法帮了某位队员
You ever give that same boost to your swimmers there?
他们应该会留着那些样本吧
They keep those old samples, don't they?
非常感谢你的访问
Oh, thank you so much for the interview.
贝克特探长  卡塞尔先生
Detective Beckett, Mr. Castle.
调查怎么样了  有新线索吗
How goes the investigation? Any new leads?
事实上  我们找到了突破口
Actually, we think we caught a break.
-那真是太好了  -嗯
- Well, that's great. - Mm-hmm.
是的  对其他人挺好  对你就不太妙了
Yes, it is. Well, for everyone except you.
我...我不...
I... I don't--
省省吧  罗博
Drop the act, Rob.
我们知道你是怎么变成火箭的
We know how you got to be the Rocket.
罗姆教练告诉了我们
Coach Rome told us about
早在维明顿他是怎么给你加油的
how he gave you rocket fuel back in Wilmington
直到助你参加了奥运会都没有停手
and didn't stop until you went all the way.
你到底在说什么鬼话
What the hell are you talking about?
我从不作弊  有检测结果为证
I have never juiced. I have the test results to prove it.
是的  但是他们检测的东西不对
Yeah, but they weren't testing for the right thing.
我们检查了你最近一次
We checked your blood samples
摘金比赛的血液样本
from the last gold medal race you won
与扎克在布莱恩车里发现的
against the designer steroids
特制类固醇做了对比
that Zack found in Brian's car.
药检呈阳性
It came back positive.
那一定是搞错了
There was a mistake.
凭借药检结果  我们拿到了搜查令
And then off of that, we got a warrant
对你酒店的房间进行了搜查  我们发现了
to search your hotel room, where we found
一件衬衣上带有氯  纯氯
a shirt with chlorine on it--pure chlorine--
杀死扎克的那种氯
the kind that killed zack.
现在我们正在等待DNA检测结果
We're waiting for D.N.A. test results right now.
不对  我一整晚都在酒吧待着
No, I was at Buddha Bar the whole night.
那里人满为患  你可以轻而易举
And it was packed there. You could've easily slipped out
不引起任何注意的溜出去再赶回来
and come back without anyone noticing.
荒唐透顶
This is ridiculous.
我为什么要杀扎克
Why would I kill Zack?
因为当扎克在布莱恩车中发现了类固醇
Because when Zack found steroids in Brian's car,
他不知如何是好
He was conflicted about what to do.
所以他向一个
So he sought counsel
他确信可以相信的人寻求建议
from the one guy he knew he could trust--
这个人是个"美国队长"  战功赫赫
Captain America, chest full of medals,
全民偶像
guy on the cereal box.
只是你意识到
Only you realized,
罗姆教练给你和布莱恩使用了
Coach Rome had given Brian the same steroids
同样的类固醇
he had given to you.
你也知道如果扎克说出去
And you knew that if Zack talked,
你的事也就曝光了
you would be found out.
他们会把你的名字从记录册上除去
They'd erase your name from the record books.
还会收回你所有的奖牌
They'd take away all your medals.
你将一无所有
You would lose everything.
而你绝不会让这些事情发生
And there was no way you were gonna let that happen.
转过去
Turn around.
好好看看吧  罗博
Take a long look, Rob.
你要去的那个地方
Where you're going...
我觉得那里可不会有泳池  走吧
I don't think they have pools. Let's go.
你说这真是讽刺啊
You know, it is ironic--
扎克觉得他可以信赖的人  他的导师
the one man zack thought he could trust--his mentor--
竟然成了杀他的凶手
turned out to be his killer.
是啊  说起导师  我听说你们
Yeah, speaking of mentor, I heard that you guys
昨天晚上对康拉德很是严厉啊
were pretty hard on Conrad last night.
对他严厉
Hard on him?
才不是  只是有爱的调教他一下
No, no, it was just a little friendly hazing.
听他的描述更像是
To hear him describe it, it sounds like
某人要教训他一下
someone was trying to teach him a lesson.
什么  我为什么要那么做
What? Why would I want to do that?
因为你不想让他和我在一起
Because you didn't want him to spend time with me.
-这完全是...  -真的
- That is completely-- - True?
对  好吧
Yes. Fine.
是真的  我嫉妒了
It's true. I'm jealous.
好吧  我承认了
There. I said it.
我...
I...
我只想让你专属我一个人
I want you all to myself,
而让你和另外一个作家在一起
and to have you spending time with another writer,
让我很郁闷
that upsets me.
如果这样显得我小气  那就小气好了
If that makes me petty, so be it.
我就是小气
Guilty as charged.
其实  我还觉得挺可爱的
Actually, I kinda think it's sweet.
真的
You do?
I do.
所以你完全不用再担心
And that's why you don't have to worry
我跟康拉德在一起了
about me hanging around with Conrad anymore.
从现在起  我只专属于一个作家
From now on, I am a one-writer girl.
我确实有点过意不去
I do feel kinda bad.
他毕竟是我的弟子
He is my mentee after all.
他其实也没做错什么
He really didn't do anything wrong.
我才不会过意不去
I wouldn't feel so bad.
然后他说
And then he said,
"他们以前就是这么教训我上课说话的"
"they used to do this to me for talking in class."
既然我们结案了
Hey, since, uh, we, uh, closed the case,
我们想带康拉德去赖克斯
uh, we figured we'd take Conrad
来个小型实地考察
on a little field trip up to Rikers.
我在《必死无疑》里面写了重口味的监狱场景
Yeah, I have a pretty heavy prison scene in "Seriously Dead,"
我想尽量贴近现实
and I want to get all the facts right.
你还是会把手稿发给我的吧
Will you still send me your writer's draft?
当然  等我更改了凶手后
Yes, as soon as I change the killer.
-真写的是女友啊  - 菜鸟级失误
- Girlfriend? - Rookie mistake.
-很高兴认识你  艾利克斯  -我也是
- It was nice to meet you, Alex. - You, too.
走吧
Come on.
男人也能做缪斯  是不是  伙计
So... A dude can be a muse, right, bro?
我是说  也不是很怪  对吧
I mean, that's not weird or anything, is it?
-不  一点儿也不怪  -一点儿也不
- No, it's not weird. - No. Mnh-mnh.
好吧
Nah. Yeah.
还是有点儿怪
That's a little weird.
对
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
随时效劳
Always.